And it's this time again, when we look at the podium of how our models are performing across the board.
이번에도 시상대에 올랐습니다 모델들의 퍼포먼스를 감상해 보죠
You already know the answer, but we should look at it anyway and and and have a giggle.
이미 답을 아시지만 그래도 한번 보고 웃어야겠어요
Uh, so we first look at the constant model that just guesses the average value from the training data
먼저 훈련 데이터 세트에서 평균 값을 추측하는 상수 모델을 살펴보죠
And if we look at that number, it was 146.
그 숫자를 보면 146이었죠
It's looking distinctly lower in here right now.
확실히 더 낮아 보여요
And I think you probably know why.
이유는 아실 거예요
Uh, then we looked at a traditional machine learning model that was able to beat the average, which
그리고 전통적인 머신 러닝 모델을 살펴봤는데 평균을 넘을 수 있었어요 그러길
we would hope it would, but not by masses.
바라지만 대다수는 아니었죠
Uh, we looked at the random forest approach, which was the best of the traditional machine learning
무작위 숲 접근법을 살펴봤는데 97년에 나온 전통적인 머신
approaches coming in at 97.
러닝 접근법 중 최고였어요
We did compare it with a human being and showed that human could beat the basic, simple features,
인간과 비교해 보니 인간은 단순한 기본 특징을 이길 수 있었지만
but was beaten by random forest model.
숲의 모델에 지고 말았죠
Uh, GPT four zero was the best of the various frontier models we looked at, and absolutely crushed
GPT 40은 다양한 프런티어 모델 중 최고였어요 인간을
it with 76 way outperforming this human.
76배나 능가하며 완벽하게 해냈죠
And then today we've looked at the, uh, fine tuned bass llama, 3.18 billion parameters quantized
오늘은 미세하게 조율된 베이스 라마 3을 살펴봤어요 180억 매개 변수가 4분의 1로 양분화됐어요
Uh, and we saw that that was at 396, devastatingly bad.
396도라는 걸 확인했는데 정말 심각했어요
Uh, and it was only slightly better when we quantized to eight bits, instead coming in at $301 of
8비트로 양자화했을 때가 약간 더 나았습니다 오차가 301달러로 늘었죠
Uh, so clearly we're off to a bad start with llama 3.1, but in some ways that's exciting because the
라마 3은 시작이 안 좋네요 1점이지만 도전이 시작됐으니 어떤 면에선
challenge is on.
신나죠
Uh, we've got the the model here ready for us to try and explore how we can make it better.
이 모델을 가지고 어떻게 개선할지 시험해 볼 거예요
And our target is to try and be competitive with a model like GPT four, which is, you know, has trillions
저희 목표는 GPT 4 같은 모델과 경쟁하는 겁니다 매개 변수가 수조 개나
of parameters.
되죠
If we can be competitive with that in this particular task, and we can do it with an open source model
이 특정 작업에서 경쟁력을 갖추고 무료 오픈 소스 모델로
that's for free, then we have achieved a great thing.
작업할 수 있다면 우린 대단한 걸 이룬 거죠
Okay.
네
And so in summary, at this point, at this juncture, you have reached 80% of your way in this journey
요약하자면, 이 시점에서 여러분은 80%의 여정을 마쳤는데
and that is absolutely fantastic.
정말 대단한 거예요
I'm so happy you.
정말 기뻐요
Are sticking at it.
계속 물고 늘어져요
I'm so happy you're here.
와줘서 정말 기뻐요
I got to tell you, the 20% that's still to come.
아직 20%가 안 왔어요
It's the best.
최고예요
It is the best.
그게 최고죠
The juiciest content is what's to come.
가장 맛있는 콘텐츠는 다음에 나올 거예요
As we look at training this model.
이 모델을 훈련할 때요
And then in the finale next week, we really put everything together.
다음 주 결승전에선 모든 걸 합쳤어요 TUZ TUZ TOZ TUZ
I mean, it's just it's going to be a crescendo.
점점 더 커질 거예요
It's going to get better and better.
Get it, get it, get it, get it, get 갈수록 더 좋아질 거예요
Hang in there.
조금만 참아요
All of the good stuff is to come.
좋은 건 다 나올 거예요
So what we're doing next time, there's some more hyperparameters.
다음 시간에는 hyperperameter를 더 할 거예요
I know that these hyperparameters can be a bit grueling, but this is where the really important stuff
하이퍼파라미터는 좀 힘들 수도 있지만 정말 중요한 걸 배우는 비트예요
So there's some hyperparameters that control training that I'll explain to you.
hyperperameter가 있어요 컨트롤 훈련이죠 설명해 드릴게요
We're then going to set up something called a supervised fine tuning SFT trainer, which is where it
그런 다음 감독자 미세 조정 SFT 트레이너를 설치할 거예요 여기서 모든 게
all happens.
이뤄지죠
And then we're going to kick off training.
그리고 훈련을 시작할 거예요
You're going to be training your own proprietary large language model, uh, based on, uh, llama 3.1
여러분은 독자적인 대형 언어 모델을 훈련하게 될 겁니다 라마 3을 기반으로요 1단계 모델이죠
And we're going to be doing it, uh, in the next session.
다음 세션에서 그걸 할 거예요
So I will see you there.
그럼 거기서 봐요